It's always important for a running back to continue with positive gains to be the person that initiates the contact.
He should never be the one that takes a hit.
We never want to see our running back coming out of the backfield, taking a hand off and cower up when the defender comes up to hit him and drive him backwards.
If that happens, he's probably not going to play running back very much longer.
What we always want to see him do is initiate contact in order to get as much positive yardage as they can.
They're going to get hit anyway, so they might as well be the hitter, not the hit tee.
You never want to be the person taking the contact; you want to be the one dishing out the punishment.
What we want to see is once he takes the hand off we want to see him with that good, low body lean and we want to see him put the contact on and drive through the hole in order to pick up a positive gain.
So, always remember, initiate the contact.
Never be the guy that gets hit.
We always want positive yardage after the carry.